m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：小豆丁  冰蓝  猫中之王  独醉
校对：猫中之王  YY   总监   YY
后期：孤帆    时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第八季  第十三集
巴尼・斯丁森  罗宾和我订婚啦
孩子们  在2012年年末
Kids, in late 2012,
我收到了一条非常重要的短信
I received a very important text message.
巴尼叔叔和罗宾阿姨订婚了
Uncle Barney and aunt Robin were engaged.
我们这个小集体进入了无比欢乐的时光
Marking a truly happy time for our little group.
而问题是
The problem was,
我们中的某人倒是不怎么开心
one of us was definitely not happy
马文止不住地哭啊
Marvin will not stop crying.
你们觉得是什么原因  是不是肚子饿了
What do you guys think it is? Is he hungry?
肯定是这个原因
Well, that must be it!
真是一语惊醒梦中人啊  泰德
Thank you for thinking of that, Ted!
瞧瞧我们俩  只知道给他浇水
And here we were, just watering him,
让他朝阳  进行光合作用
facing him towards sun light!
抱歉  自新年起  我就没睡过觉
Sorry, I haven't slept in... January.
马文进食不是问题
Food going in isn't the problem.
排便才是  又或者说没有排便
It's what's coming out, or not coming out.
他已经3天没有便便了
He hasn't pooped in three days.
一般来说  我对脏尿布是恨之入骨
Normally, I wouln't wish one of his dirty diapers on my worst enemy.
但现在  我倒是挺想念早晨打开尿布的时光
But now, I kinda miss pop in the hood in the morning,
-看见那大条多汁  黑乎乎的...  -莉莉
- and finding that first big, juicy, black--  - Lily!
我这正吃香辣炖肉酱呢  莉莉
I'm eating chili. I'm eating chili, Lily.
彩条
confetti!
简直就是彩条大爆炸啊
Big blast of confetti!
一般来说  那孩子就是彩条喷射机啊
Normally, the kid's a confetti machine.
他就是婴儿版的雷普・泰勒
He's Rip Taylor in a diaper.
美国喜剧演员  经常以撒彩条方式登场
我有预感  这个时刻
I have a feeling at this point,
我家的雷普・泰勒又在喷"彩条"了
Rip Taylor is Rip Taylor in a diaper.
如此生动的视觉形容  这饭是不用吃了
And with that image, dinner is done.
-伙计们  -啧啧
- Hey, guys.  - Well, well, well.
新娘驾到
Here comes the bride.
最棘手的部分要开始了  对吧
Now the annoying part, right?
策划婚礼
Planning the wedding?
太无趣了  对吧
So not fun, right?
怎么说呢  我还挺期待的
I don't know-- I'm kind of looking forward to it.
好吧  那我就帮帮你吧
Fine, I'll do it for you.
首先要定好时间
First thing we need to do is set a date.
2013年5月25日
May 25, 2013.
谢谢你  泰德
Thank you, Ted.
女人说话  男人闪边
The ladies are talking.
其实  这就是婚期
Actually, that is the date.
泰德毛遂自荐  帮忙策划了一点
Ted offered to help with the planning a little.
然后呢...
And, well, uh...
这文件夹真够大的
That's a big binder.
这个吗
Oh, this?
这只是婚礼蛋糕的内容而已
This is just cakes.
对了  典礼地点选在
Anyway, we're having the ceremony
长岛上那个美丽的小教堂
at that beautiful little church out on Long Island,
也就是我和维多利亚差点结婚的地方
where Victoria almost got married-- lovely spot.
在酒店前的草坪  搭一个巨大的白色帐篷
And then we're gonna have a reception in a big white tent
用来宴请宾客
on the front lawn of the hotel.
颜色嘛  以乳白和淡紫为主
Oh, and, uh, the colors are cream and lilac.
老娘要把你碎尸万段  贱人
I will cut you, bitch.
别  莉莉...
No, L-L-Lily...
我没事  没事了
I'm cool, I'm cool.
罗宾  巴尼人呢
Hey, Robin, where's Barney?
才订婚就跑路了吗
Did he skip town already?
若真是跑了  什么时候跑的
If so, exactly what time was it?
具体时间对于赌注输赢很重要
It's important for the over/under.
巴尼没事  只是  今天早晨...
Barney's fine, it's just... well, earlier this morning...
距我答应你求婚已经三天了
So, it's been three days since I said yes.
的确
True.
你的恐慌发作的时间也越来越短
And your panic attacks are getting
次数越来越少
shorter and further apart.
我办不到  我快要窒息而亡了
I can't do this! I feel like I'm drowning!
确实如此
Also true.
看来我们可以正式算订婚了
So I guess we're officially engaged.
或许我们该通知一下父母吧
Maybe we should tell our parents.
我猜我爸已经知道了吧  你给他打过电话
I assume my dad already knows-- you did call him
得到了他的允许  对吧
and got his permission, right?
是啊  是啊  罗宾
Yeah, yeah, Robin.
你是我用几头公牛和来自东土的香料换回来的
I bought you with an ox and some spices from the East.
他要把你关在笼子里
Uh, he's gonna put you in a cage.
放在马背上  运到我那偏远的沙漠营地里
and send you on horseback to my remote desert camp.
-好了  巴尼  -慢着  我还没说完
- Okay, Barney...   - Hold on, I'm not done.
你用香水和精油沐浴净身
Where you'll be bathed in perfumes and oils
然后送至我的帐篷中
and delivered to my tent.
在你表演完那传统的七重面纱之舞后
After you perform the traditional Dance of the Seven Veils,
我们将躺在虎皮地毯上...
we'll adjourn to the tiger skin rug where we'll...
-巴尼  -罗宾
- Barney...  - Robin!
我俩若想共筑婚姻
If we're gonna build a marriage together,
就千万不要总是打断对方说话
we have got to stop interrupting each other all the time.
行吧  讲完你的故事
Fine, finish your story.
谢谢
Thank you.
翻云覆雨
Where we'll do it.
你有得到我爸的允许吗
Did you ask for my father's permission?
没有
No, I did not.
你们也知道  我爹有点小可怕
So, as some of you know, my dad is a little scary.
才有点吗  你爸堪称食死徒般的可怕
A little? Dude's a stone cold Slytherin.
他面露凶光  总感觉像是刚抽完
He always looks like he just came from slapping
某个捆在密室椅子上的人的耳光
some guy tied to a chair in a back room.
总之  我们三个一同吃午餐
Anyway, we go get lunch...
听着  我知道我警告过你
Look, I know I already told you this,
但我爸真的很可怕
but my dad is a scary guy.
拜托  我能搞定他
Please, I think I can handle...
不惧光的吸血鬼  不惧光的吸血鬼啊
Oh, vampire in the daylight, vampire in the daylight!
天啊
Oh, my God.
你好  罗宾
Hello, Robin.
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
把手拿开
Put that thing away,
给你老爸一个拥抱
Give your old man a hug.
而噩梦才刚刚开始
And then it got really scary.
我很高兴  你们能约在
I'm glad you could meet me here
我最喜欢的餐厅见面
at my favorite restaurant.
我和卡罗尔经常来这里
Carol and I come here all the time.
我...你...
I... you...
什么...怎么...  卡罗尔是谁
When... Da... who's Carol?
对哦  你还没见过卡罗尔呢
Oh, right, you haven't met Carol, um...
非常特别的女人
Very special woman.
年方48  牙科清洁师  膝下无子
48 years old, dental hygienist, no kids.
喜欢跳尊巴舞
Likes Zumba.
为了她我才搬到纽约来
She's the reason I moved to New York City.
8个月前就来了  谢谢您现在才告诉我
Eight months ago. Thanks for the call, by the way.
我以为你知道呢
Well, I figured you knew.
我在脸书页面上更新了
It's on my Facebook page.
你真应该通过我的好友申请
You really should respond to my friend request.
我经常贴一些很棒的东西
I post a lot of great stuff.
你知道什么是"网络爆红"吗
Are you familiar with memes?
一只猫竟然说
There's a cat who says,
"我想吃芝士汉堡"
"I can has cheeseburger?"
你到底怎么了
Okay, what the hell happened to you?
罗宾  我知道过去  我一直...
Robin, I know in the past, I have been...
挺冷漠的
emotionally distant.
但是卡罗尔发掘了
But Carol has brought out
我全新的一面
a whole new side of me.
我有了全新的人生观
I have a new outlook on life
无忧无虑逍遥自在  就像我的信条
a devil-may-care insouciance that embodies the credo,
"没衣服  没鞋子  没问题"
"No shirt, no shoes, no problem."
罗宾
Robin...
我变得有趣了
I'm fun now.
天啊
Oh, God.
-他变得有趣了吗  -听起来一点也不有趣啊
- He's fun now? - That does not sound fun.
孩子不该看到家长变成那个样子
No child should have to see a parent go through that.
这样的话  巴尼对见家长这件事的
Well, it probably took some of the pressure
压力应该减轻不少吧
off the Barney of it all.
您好  先生
Sir, hi.
我叫巴尼・斯丁森
My name is Barney Stinson.
这是巴尼吗
This is Barney?
这货居然是金发
This man is blond.
成熟男人才不会留金发呢
Grown men are not blond.
爸爸
Dad.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
你的头发...
That's a very...
颜色真搞笑
fun hair color.
那不算什么  他和我见面时第一句话是
That's nothing-- when he met me, his first words were,
-女衬衫不错  -你穿的就是女衬衫
- "Nice blouse" - You were wearing a blouse.
才不是女衬衫呢
It was not a blouse!
太好了  你们都在
Oh, great. You're all here.
商讨一下婚礼乐队的事吧
Let's talk about our wedding band.
你们觉得他们应该有多嗨
How much do you guys think they should rock?
我觉得应该嗨翻天
'Cause I vote, a million.
是啊  我们早就定好DJ了啊
Yeah, yeah, I think we already settled on a DJ, so...
莉莉  你还记得你们结婚时
Lily, do you remember the band you guys
差点请的乐队吗
almost hired for your wedding?
何止记得
Remember them?
我可以帮你打电话预定
I'll call them up and book them for you.
只要你一句话
Just say the word.
是啊  是啊  我觉得我们又绕回来
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I feel like we keep coming back
说DJ的事了
to this DJ thing.
你觉得呢  宝贝
What do you think, baby?
我觉得现在决定  还为时尚早
Yeah, I don't think anyone should book anything right now.
为什么
Why not?
我要去标有"意大利面"的洗手间了
Well, I am going to go the room marked "Spaghettis,"
但愿那是女厕
which I'm hoping is the ladies room.
"肉球"什么的应该是指男厕  对吧
"Meatballs" Has to be men's, right?
虽然我搞不懂"鱿鱼"代表的是什么鬼东西
I don't know what the hell "Calamaris" Is.
先生  我...
Sir, I-I-I...
我不准
Permission denied.
结果  "意大利面"是男厕
And it turns out, "Spaghettis" are men.
我还看见了一根"面条"
I saw a noodle.
-他不同意吗  -对啊  我不知道该如何是好
- He said no? - Yeah, I don't know what we're gonna do.
别紧张  宝贝  交给我
Relax, baby. I got this.
我知道如何说服他人
I know how to be persuasive.
第二天  巴尼叔叔约罗宾的爸爸
The next day, Uncle Barney met Robin's dad
在同一家餐厅吃午饭
for lunch at the same restaurant.
这次  他制定了计划
This time, with a plan.
您好  特布罗斯基先生
Hello, Mr. Scherbatsky.
我想我第一次没给您留下好印象
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
你现在吸引到我的注意了
You have my attention.
我让"肉球"待在家里
I left the meatball at home
这样我们就能"面"对"面"谈谈
so I could talk to you spaghetti to spaghetti.
先生
Sir...
我是诚心诚意想娶您的女儿
I'm very serious about marrying your daughter.
巴尼  我想和罗宾的妈妈结婚时
Barney, when I wanted to marry Robin's mother,
我赤手空拳屠杀了
I slaughtered a whole family of bears
一窝熊
with my bare hands.
我把熊皮
I gave the pelts
和熊肉给她爸爸作为聘礼
and the bear meat to her father as tribute.
你知道这在加拿大叫什么吗
You know what we call that in Canada?
规矩
Manners.
你们想来一杯"山崩"饮料吗
Would either of you like a mudslide?
我刚"崩"过了  谢谢
I just had one. Thank you.
我要一杯浮彩绚丽彩虹奶昔
I'll have a Jazzy Pizzazzy Razzleberry Rainbow Milkshake
上面插一根弯吸管
with a swirly straw?
你忘了说那个神奇的[请]字哦
You didn't say the magic word.
小的这就去拿您的饮料
I'll go get your drink.
还哭着呢
Still crying, huh?
对  我们试尽了一切办法
Yeah. We've tried everything short
除了让他抽烟和喝咖啡
of a pack of smokes and a cup of coffee.
他尿布还是干干净净  没有粑粑
Still nothing but clean dipeys.
只剩下一个解释了
There's only one explanation for this.
马文自己学会了上厕所
Marvin has potty-trained himself.
他趁我们睡觉时去厕所
He sneaks into the bathroom while we're sleeping.
我去让巴尼看监控录像
I'll ask Barney to check the tapes.
巴尼在咱家厕所装了摄像头吗
Barney has cameras in our bathroom?!
你难道觉得他没有吗
Well, I mean, don't you think?
-你们好  -罗宾  真好
- Hey, guys. - Robin, good.
你来了  坏消息
You're here. Bad news.
你想要的那婚礼乐队5月25日已经被预定了
That wedding band you wanted is booked for May 25.
不是吧  你打算怎么办
Oh, no. What are you gonna do?
对了  我有个主意
Oh! Oh, hey! Here's an idea.
天啊  泰德  如果你提议请DJ
Oh, God, Ted, if you suggest a DJ...
才不是
Far from it.
我是想推荐一支乐队
I was going to suggest a band.
爵士乐队  其代表作Celebration是婚礼常用曲
名字叫库尔伙伴
A band called... Kool and the Gang.
罗宾
Robin,
你愿意让我
would you like for me
预定库尔伙伴在你的婚礼上表演吗
to get Kool and the Gang to play at your wedding?
应该  可以吧
Uh... I... yeah, guess so.
他们邀请朋友来可以吗
And would it be okay if they invited their friends,
碧昂斯  阿巴乐队
Beyonce and-and ABBA,
比吉斯乐队
and the Bee Gees,
旅途乐队
and Journey,
皇后乐队
and Queen?
什么  你说什么
What? You're...? What are you say...?
这一切怎么可能办到
How... how is that even possible?
我告诉你怎么办到
I'll tell you how.
请个DJ
You hire a DJ.
小手一转  万事俱备
Wicka-wicka-wicka-burn.
天啊  这大概是
Ugh! God, this is, like,
我爸第十五次给我发送好友申请了
the fifteenth time my dad has sent me a friend request.
我干脆点"接受"算了
I'm just gonna hit "Accept."
-千万不行  -别这样  罗宾
- No, no, no. - No, no, no, no, don't do it, Robin.
你不会想看见那扇门背后都藏着什么
You don't want to see what's behind that door.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
他说的是
He's talking about
风靡美国的情色小说
我妈为《五十度灰》写的两千字书评
my mom's 2,000-word review of Fifty Shades of Grey.
其中有十四个词都是"阴部"
And 14 of those words were "Vulva."
你会收到无数多的邀请
You're gonna get endless requests to play some game
邀你去玩黑帮游戏或者开心农场
that has something to do with gangsters and farming.
还有令人尴尬的高中时代
Never mind the embarrassing cheerleading photos
参加拉拉队的照片
from high school.
-我都跪求我我妈烧掉那些照片了  -罗宾
- Begged my mom to burn those. - Robin,
相信我
trust me,
接受父母的好友申请  绝对没有好下场
no good can come from accepting that friend request.
我大概是误导了你们大家
Yeah, I-I think I may have given you guys the wrong impression.
我爸他其实不是个坏人
Okay, my dad is actually not that bad of a guy.
下手吧  巴尼  果断扣下扳机
Do it, Barney. Squeeze that trigger.
人家不想做嘛
I don't want to do this.
你以为我当年想杀掉那只熊吗
Well, you think I wanted to kill that bear?
-我觉得你是想的  -你说得对
- Yeah, kind of. - Oh, yeah, you're right.
我下不了手
I can't do this.
你们在搞什么呢
What... what the hell is this?!
你爸是个疯子
Your dad is crazy!
他非逼我杀了棉花酱不可
He wanted me to kill Fluffernutter!
告诉你不要给他取名字
I told you not to give him a name!
我就取了
Well, I did!
我不但取了名  还帮他编了个来历
I gave him a name and a backstory!
他来自一个魔法小兔窝
He comes from a magical rabbit warren
一家老小住在老锈的拖拉机下
underneath the old rusty tractor.
他出生时先天不足  但却坚韧地活了下来
He was the runt of the litter, but he persevered.
-他...  -把枪给我  还给我
- He... - Oh, give me this. Give it to me!
爸  你就没有什么事要告诉我吗
Dad, is there, um, something you want to tell me?
80年代初期  我曾为中央情报局干过脏活
Well, in the early '80s, I did some wet work for the CIA.
爸  睡前故事我记忆犹新
Yes, Daddy, I remember the bedtime stories.
不  我指的是你的脸书
No, I'm, uh, talking about your Facebook page?
上面写着你结婚了
It says you're married.
那个
Well...
是的 卡罗尔和我当时在基拉戈
yes, uh, Carol and I were in Key Largo
老牌乡村摇滚歌星
参加吉米・布菲特的演唱会
at a performance of the recording artist James Buffett.
我们是铁杆的"鹦鹉头"
We're what are known as Parrotheads.
鹦鹉头是吉米・布菲特粉丝团的昵称
总而言之  一来二去
And, uh, well, one thing led to the other, and, uh...
我们就结婚了
we got married.
你不打算告诉我这件事吗
You didn't want to tell me about it?
我发脸书了啊  在脸书上宣布了
I Facebooked it... on Facebook.
好吧  知道吗  老爸
Okay, you know what, Dad?
既然你不想让我和你的私生活
Since you obviously have no interest in involving me
扯上关系  我就告诉你
in your personal life, I may as well tell you:
巴尼和我已经订婚了
Barney and I are already engaged.
她说得没错
That's right.
我是你的坚强后盾  罗宾
I'm behind you on this, Robin.
坚定地躲在你背后
Directly behind you.
总之  事情就是这样
Anyway, this is happening.
既然你不邀请我参加你的婚礼
And since I wasn't invited to your wedding,
你也别想来参加我的婚礼
you're not invited to mine.
再见吧
Good-bye.
不好了
Oh, no!
棉花酱尿了我一裤子
Fluffernutter peed all over my pants!
我给那个婚礼乐队的经纪人打了电话
So, I just called up that wedding band's road manager
要来了预定25号的人的电话
to get the number of the people who booked them for the 25th,
希望能塞点钱让他们取消预定
so I could bribe them into giving up the band.
你都做了什么  这实在太卑鄙了
You did what?! That is so dishonest!
不管接下来发生了什么  我们都一致同意
No matter what happens next, I think we can all agree,
你真是卑鄙无耻  莉莉
you're in the wrong here, Lily.
那就是你的电话  泰德
It's your number, Ted.
好吧  被你逮到了
All right, you got me!
我付了乐队一笔无法退还的定金
I put a non-refundable deposit on that band
好让巴尼和罗宾订不到他们
to keep Barney and Robin from booking them.
我本来可以成功骗过你们
And I would've gotten away with it
如果这计划不是那么愚蠢又那么昂贵的话
if it wasn't a really stupid and expensive plan.
老兄  你干嘛要这么做
Dude, why would you do that?
我不觉得这有什么重要的
I don't see what the big deal is.
重要的是罗宾值得拥有更好的选择
The big deal is Robin deserves better
而不是某支蹩脚又不靠谱的乐队
than some crappy, unreliable band!
乐队表面看起来是不错
Sure, bands seem cool
衣服帅  举手抬足都精心排练过
with their nice suits and their well-rehearsed moves,
可老实说  乐队总会让人失望
but let's be honest: bands let you down.
他们会撒谎  欺骗
They-They cheat, they deceive,
他们睡遍了纽约市的每个女人
and God knows they've slept with every girl in New York City.
我只是不敢相信
I just, I can't believe
罗宾要忍受嫁给...
Robin is going through with marrying...
请乐队这个想法
the idea of getting a band.
这句话没有一点语法错误哦
And that is, that's a perfectly normal way to phrase that.
好吧  泰德  去酒吧  马上走
Okay, Ted, bar. Now.
想得美
Nice try.
你就想把孩子丢给我
You're gonna stick me with that baby
然后去酒吧花五分钟
so that you guys can spend five minutes
解决他的爱情烦恼
sorting out his love life,
接下来的一小时就是喝得醉醺醺
followed by an hour of you getting drunk
大玩《无间道风云》的角色扮演
and pretending to be in The Departed.
好吧好吧  我很抱歉  莉莉
You know what? I'm sorry, Lily, okay?
可我只想知道一件事
But I just need to know:
-你是警察吗  -我不是警察
- Are you a cop? - I'm not a cop!
我来处理这事
I got this.
泰德  你跟我  上楼
Ted, you, me, upstairs.
去楼顶  马上走
Roof. Now.
-哈  现在一月寒冬  -快走
- What? It's January. - Move!
废话就不说了
Let's cut the crap.
我俩都冻得要死
We're both freezing--
所以赶紧说完  我们就可以下楼了
just say it and we can go downstairs.
说什么啊
Say what?
说你有多不爽
Say how much you hate
罗宾要和巴尼结婚的事
that Robin and Barney are getting married.
什么  不  我
What? No. I...
我为他们感到高兴啊
I'm happy for them.
我还鼓励罗宾去追巴尼
I-I encouraged Robin to go after Barney.
我知道  因为你以为自己可以放手
I know-- because you thought you were okay letting her go.
但现在她真的要嫁人了
But now that she's really gone,
你大受打击
it hurts.
孩子们  在那个时候
Kids, at that point in my life,
我的人生中已经受过不少次"打击"了
I'd been hurt quite a few times already.
今天  我们要带上友情手链
Today, we're gonna braid friendship bracelets.
我深深地爱上了*
*I fell in love...
这件事其实很简单
There is a very simple explana... ah!
有一次我正在打网球
This one time, I was playing tennis, and...
对了  死尿斯比  还记得那次你在
Hey, Schmosby, remember when you dookied
湖边尿裤子的事吗
in your pants down by the lake?
真不敢相信
Unbelievable!
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
不爱
No.
但当我看到那条短信
But when I saw that text message,
发现罗宾已经订婚时
and found out Robin was engaged,
巴尼・斯丁森  罗宾和我订婚啦
感觉就像
it was like:
真不敢相信
Unbelievable!
不爱
No.
这些加起来  再乘以一百万倍
...times a million.
我真心为他们高兴
I am happy for them.
你只敢让自己这样说
Is all you'll let yourself say out loud,
因为只要你说了任何相反的话
because if you said anything to the contrary, well,
你就会变成
that would make you
这屋顶上最可怕的人
the most awful person on this rooftop.
我打算让你一吐为快
So, I'm gonna give you an out.
你打算怎么做
And how are you gonna do that?
我会说出更可怕的话
By saying something that is even more awful.
什么话
Like what?
有时候我会希望自己不是一个母亲
Sometimes I wish I wasn't a mom.
有时候我想收拾好行李
Sometimes I want to pack a bag
半夜悄悄离开  不再回来
and leave in the middle of the night and not come back.
罗宾不应该嫁给巴尼
Robin shouldn't be with Barney,
她应该嫁给我
she should be with me.
你说真的吗
You serious?
我不知道
I don't know.
我喜欢做母亲
I mean, I love being a mom, and...
我好爱好爱马文
I love Marvin so much.
但是
But...
你还记得
but do you remember
我想做艺术家的时候吗
when I wanted to be an artist?
艺术是我的人生意义
Art was my whole life.
而现在我已经好几个月
And-and now it's been months
没有拿起画笔了
since I've even picked up a brush.
我白天在幼儿园的工作就是照顾孩子
I-I spend the whole day taking care of kids at my job,
然后回到家  还是一样
and I come home and it's more of the same.
只是
It just...
从来没有休息的时候...
It never lets up, it...
真的真的好累  泰德
It's just really, really hard, Ted.
你有跟马修讲过你的感受吗
Have you talked to Marshall about how you feel?
你有跟罗宾讲过你的感受吗
Have you talked to Robin about how you feel?
说得好
Fair enough.
我想我们都必须接受人生的缺憾
I just think we have to accept our lots in life,
我必须做一位母亲
and I have to be a mom to a...
做一位漂亮可爱
a beautiful, wonderful--
有点小便秘的
if slightly constipated--
小男孩的母亲
little boy, and...
你必须让罗宾和巴尼在婚礼上请乐队
you have to let Robin and Barney get a band.
好吧  看看尿布里有什么
All right, let's see what's in this dipey.
什么也没有
Nothing.
绝对是什么也没有
Absolutely nothing.
你终于肯对你老爸笑了吗
Are you finally giving Daddy a smile?
上帝啊
Oh, God!
不  当时喷的可不是彩条
And, no, it wasn't confetti.
上帝啊
Oh! Oh, God!
求你了
Please!
好多的"彩条"啊
Holy confetti.
那天晚上  罗宾同意
That night, Robin agreed
再见她父亲一次
to meet her dad one more time.
你爸有话要说
Your Dad has something to say.
抱歉我没问你意见就结婚了
I'm sorry for getting married without consulting you.
这是我的错
It was wrong of me.
好了  罗宾
There. Now, Robin...
我知道只有道歉  是不能解决问题的
I know that no mere apology will fix this.
所以
And that is why
我已经要求卡罗尔和我离婚
I've asked Carol for a divorce.
什么
What?!
她的心都碎了  可以理解
She's heartbroken, understandably.
可能会自杀
Possibly suicidal.
我没有让他...
I did not tell him...
但如果付出这样的代价
But if that's the price
才能得到我女儿的爱
for my daughter's love...
我很乐意这个代价让卡罗尔来付
then I will gladly let Carol pay it.
这不是你想要的吗
Was that not what you wanted?
你想知道我要什么吗
You want to know what I want?
一个普通的爸爸  就是这样
A normal dad. That's all.
我要你同意这个金发男子
I want you to give this blond guy
娶我为妻
permission to marry me.
来参加我的婚礼  将我交给他
Come to the wedding, give me away,
笑着拍照  然后...
smile in the pictures, and then...
像普通父亲一样  和我跳舞
dance with me like a normal dad.
这个要求很过分吗
Is that too much to ask?
当然不会
"Of course not.
罗宾  我亲爱的女儿
Oh, Robin, my darling girl,
我当然会这样做
of course I'll do all stuff.
我爱你  我为你感到骄傲
I love you and I'm proud of you."
-他没这样说吧  -没
- He didn't say that? - No.
好吧  只跳一支舞
Fine. One dance--
舞曲是《天堂的芝士汉堡》
"Cheeseburger in Paradise."
必须得由卡罗尔演唱
And Carol's going to sing it.
我们婚礼见
Well, see you at the wedding.
但这是非常了不起的事
But it's kind of amazing.
他这辈子从没向我道过歉
I mean, he's never apologized to me in his life.
巴尼却让他这样做了
Barney made it happen.
他肯定是真的很爱我
He must really love me.
傻子才会不爱你
Well, he'd be crazy not to.
我真的为你们高兴
I'm really happy for you guys.
但我依然认为你们该请DJ
But I still think you should get a DJ.
有完没完  泰德
For God's sakes, Ted.
听我说
Hear me out.
那晚我的理由强而有力
I made a pretty strong case that night,
但最后  她根本不想请DJ
but in the end, she didn't want a DJ.
她想要乐队
She wanted a band.
猜猜结果是什么
And guess what happened.
没错  乐队在最终一刻放他们鸽子了
That's right, the band cancelled at the last minute,
四个月后
我早说过他们会这样做
just like I said they would.
婚礼一周后举行  却连乐队都没有
The wedding is in a week, and no bands.
大家何时才能意识到  我从不会看走眼
When will people realize I always know what's what?
那你之前跟女同约会过一个月  怎么说
He says to the lesbian he dated for a month.
说得好
That's a fair point.
话说回来  你们不会恰好知道
Anyway, you guys wouldn't, uh, happen to know
有什么优秀的婚礼乐队
of any good wedding bands
可以临危受命吧
available at the last minute, would you?
泰德  你相信命运吗
Ted, do you believe in destiny?
看来你真是不认识我啊
You really don't know me, do you?
我们刚和我的前室友吃完早午餐
We just had brunch with my ex-roommate.
那个贝斯手吗
The bass player?
不  她不仅仅是贝斯手
No, she's not just a bass player.
她是大纽约三州最优秀的
She's a bass player in the best wedding band
婚礼乐队的贝斯手
in the tri-state area.
他们本来这周末有场演出
They had a gig lined up for this weekend,
但今早取消了
but it just fell through this morning.
我的朋友  你将是婚礼的救世主
You, my friend, are gonna save that wedding.
你们有认识什么DJ吗
Do you know any DJs?
哥们  拜托
Dude, come on.
别纠结了  兄弟  别纠结了
Let it go, bro. Just let it go.
好的  好的
All right, all right, all right.
我想
Well, I guess, uh...
碰到你们真是一件幸运的事
Guess it's a lucky thing I ran into you guys.
孩子们  "幸运"完全不足以形容我有多幸运
And, kids, "Lucky" doesn't even begin to describe it.
因为如果巴尼和罗宾听了我的白痴建议
Because if Barney and Robin had taken my stupid advice
请了DJ
and hired a DJ...
我就永远不会碰到你们的母亲
...I never would have met your mother.